Laura Bermudez

Software Engineer

Address Kirkland, WA

Phone 2069729255

E-mail laurabermudezg@gmail.com

GitHub https://github.com/lbeagleeyes

Coding Boot Camp Portfolio

https://lbeagleeyes.github.io/

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/laura-bermudez-garcia

Software Engineer with BS in Computer Science + 10 years of experience, currently attending a Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp at the University of Washington, fully bilingual English/Spanish, interested in complete software development life cycle, passionate about user-centered design, with programming skills in C/C++, .Net, and SQL, using agile methodologies. Able to work as a liaison between technical and non-technical teams due to excellent communication skills, experience gathering requirements and mockup design.

Experience

2011-08 - Software Engineer / Systems Analyst

2014-09

Intel Corporation

- .Net C# developer for a data analysis tool that logs tens of thousands of data at a second interval in more than 200 MS SQL and IIS web servers across continents with a user interface that enables data visualization for monitoring and analysis through graphing, playing live data, and information share.
- .Net C# (HTML5, MVC, Javascript, JQuery) developer for fab construction project that consolidates 3 applications in one to improve customer's productivity and user experience
- As a systems analyst, gathered requirements, developed mock-ups and created user stories to improve communication between customers and developers. Organized focus groups and testing sessions to receive proper feedback on time while using Agile Methodologies and Kanban to plan, track and prioritize work daily.

2009-12 - **Software Developer**

2011-07

Desert Development Company

- C++ software developer for a new games suite making good use of design patterns and SCRUM methodology.
- Developed frameworks in C++ for server and in Actionscript 3.0 for flash client that significantly increased development productivity.

2007-04 - **Software Engineer**

2010-02

Western Union

- Coordinator between teams to deliver new releases worldwide, gathering requirements from different regions to design and develop new features using C/C++ with MFC, ASP and SQL Server technologies for core business money transfer software distribution system.
- Winner of a quarterly award for excellent teamwork during a national Money Transfer software roll out for US and Canada.

2006-02 - **Software Engineer**

2007-03

Align Technology

- Improved company's productivity through requirements gathering and development of new features for a C++/MFC 3D graphics application used to model orthodontic treatments.
- Restructured Requirements Gathering and Software Validation processes for Orthodontic Treatments software development.
- Improved the company's knowledge management by developing web applications in PHP, JavaScript and MySql

2005-07 - Software Quality Engineer

2006-02

Avantica Technologies

• Redesigned test plan to expand the testing done throughout all the features of a secure email web application. Performed black box testing in UNIX, Linux and Windows platforms.

Teaching Experience

2007-06

University of Costa Rica

- Tutor for basic and intermediate programming in Java and C++.
- Software engineering substitute teacher: Guided students through the complete development life cycle of a software system developed using UML and .Net.
- Computer Principles teacher: Used project oriented teaching to help students from other engineering careers learn how to program in C.

Education

2019-02 -	University of Washington, Full Stack Web Developer Coding Bootcamp
2019-08	

University of Washington, Continuing Education Certificate in Software Product

2018-05 Management

2013 Human Factors International - Certified Usability Analyst Courses

User Centered Analysis and Practical Usability Testing

2006 American Society for Quality, Certified Software Quality Engineer

1999-03 - University of Costa Rica, bachelor's degree in Computer Science

2004-07



C/C++, C#.Net

Javascript, JQuery, Node.js

html, css

SQL

Agile Software Development

Languages

Spanish

Native

English

Toefl iBT: 113/120